Kouassi Kevin Kouadio

Address: 180 Prospect St. Apt. C5 East Orange, NJ, 07017 **Phone**: (862) 339 8389 | **Email**: kevkouadio@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kouassi-kevin-kouadio-b731a071/

GitHub: https://github.com/kevkouadio | Portfolio:http://kevkouadio.tk/ or

https://kevkouadio.github.io/kk-portofolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with Aviation Quality Assurance and Customer Services background. I graduated from Rutgers University with a Full Stack Web Development Certificate. After a degree in Marketing and strong experience in Administration Management, I am a great problem solver and I can work under pressure. I am constantly striving to learn new skills to improve my work and its impact.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

PROJECTS

Name: CMS of a restaurant website.

App GitHub Repo: https://github.com/kevkouadio/Project2

Deployed link: https://restaurant-cms-project2.herokuapp.com/login

Description: it is a CMS App that would allow a Restaurant owner to be able to post new dishes to

her/his restaurant website so that customers can view and order online.

Tools & languages used: HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, Node and Express Web server

Handlebars, MySql database, Sequelize.

Responsibilities: It was my idea so I was the project manager. I did all the backend of the app

while the others focused on the front end.

Name: NoteDrop

App GitHub Repo: https://github.com/kevkouadio/Projet-1
Deployed link: https://kevkouadio.github.io/Projet-1/

Description: It is an app that displays the top 10 hits of any artist with the possibility to view the lyrics of each song. It also features the upcoming event of the searched artist with the possibility to buy the event tickets.

Tools & languages used: HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript as well as *Genuis* and *Bands in Town* APIs.

My **Responsibilities** for that project was focused on the JavaScript part which consisted on the APIs and DOM manipulation. I also took care of the media query of the CSS.

EXPERIENCE

From September 2018 to March 2020: Cabin Maintenance Auditor, Delta Airlines & Air Canada Auditing Project for Andy Frain Services - Newark, NJ

Duties: -Quality Assurance Audit of aircraft interior. -Quality Assurance Audit of aircraft exterior paint. -Quality Assurance Audit of airport operations. -Interaction with client -Interaction with client's vendors Production of reports using audit specific software

From February 2018 to February 2020: Part-time Airline Customer Service Agent - Gate Lead for Worldwide Flight Services (El Al Airline & Air China) - Newark, NJ

Duties: Check in Passengers, preparation and issuance of tickets and itineraries, computation of fares, checking baggage, collection of excess baggage charges, providing passengers with general travel information; meets aircraft at gate, perform arrival tasks at the CBP and passport control, performs duties in the departure lounges or at boarding gates, coordinate boarding of passengers at the gate, completes all necessary arrangements for accommodating passengers holding reservations, standbys and their luggage, determines flight close-out time and prepares, completes and checks various flight forms for accuracy, invalidates tickets and completes post-departure procedures and other duties and functions related to the foregoing as directed by management.

From February 2013 to July 2016: **National Federation and Sport Assistant Africa for the International Basketball Federation (FIBA)** – Abidjan, Ivory Coast

Duties: - Coordination of the African Basketball Federations development programs - Relationship FIBA Africa / African National Federations - Coordination and Administration of Training activities for African technical managers (referees, coaches, commissioners.) - Assist the African National Federation & Sport Manager in different administrative tasks. - Support in organization of African 3x3 Basketball competitions. - Support and training on digital tools used in African 3x3 Basketball competitions.

EDUCATION

December 2020: **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development** form Rutgers University Coding Bootcamp.

August 2014: **Bachelor in Marketing Management** from Legacy Institute of Abidjan (Ivory Coast) – Abidjan.

February 2006: **Bachelor of Teaching Letters in English Language & Civilization** from University Felix Houphouet Boigny of Cocody (Ivory Coast) – Abidjan

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Spoken languages: French, Native and English, Advanced.

Verified International Academic Qualifications Educational Credential - Assessment by the **World Educational Services**.